

MANUEL MARTINS

PhD Candidate

繭

22 December 1993



Porto, Portugal

Profile

Abstract thinker Ouick learner Effective communicator Team worker Cheerful and international Mag andere neugierige Leute

Reach me

+351 91 947 3307

@

manueljrcsm@gmail.com

in

manueljrcsm

github.com/manueljrcsm

Languages

Portuguese	
English	
German	
	_
Spanish	
French	

About me

I am a mathematician transitioning from academia to industry. I have done research, programming, tutoring, also lived abroad 7+ years (Germany, Netherlands), learned other cultures and ways of thinking, now it is time to try something new close to home.

I love being challenged and sharing what I learn. I can be competitive but I take pride in helping others thrive. Empathy, curiosity and wit are some of the traits I value the most.

Interests: Machine-learning, recursive programming, algorithm design.

Education

Technische Universität Dresden, Ph.D. Mathematics 2017-2024 Quantum groups acting transitively on singular curves. 1 publication. 5 invited talks. Supplementary coursework in applied maths: Risk Theory and Modelling, Scientific Computing in C++, Object Oriented Programming in Java

Universidade do Porto, M.Sc. Mathematics 2014-2016 Dissertation "Hopf Algebras and Ore Extensions". Grade 18/20. Erasmus, VU Amsterdam, Netherlands, Jan - Jul 2015

Universidade do Porto, B.Sc. Mathematics 2011-2014 Awarded 6 prizes, incl. highest classfication in the class of 2014. Grade 19/20.

Experience

Research Assistant TU Dresden

2017

2016

Research, seminar participation, teaching assistant in Differential Geometry. Formally employed by the university before being awarded a full PhD scholarship.

Research Scholar Fundação Calouste Gulbenkian, CMUP 2012-2014, Awarded introduction-to-research grants Novos Talentos em Matemática for two consecutive year. 1 publication. 2 summer schools. 2 yearly reports and presentations. 1 three-month research grant in Algebraic Geometry in Fall 2016.

Tutoring, Monitor Private, U. Porto

2012-2023

Several highschool and university students in preparation for exams or thesis revision. Monitor during summer schools with highschool students in Sep 2011 and Sep 2013.

Abstract Mathematics

Pvthon Matlab Java

During my PhD I wrote an algebraic symbolic calculator in Python to automate computations in noncommutative algebras.

Experienced Git and Latex user. Knowledge of MS Office and collaboration software.

Currently learning SQL and implementations of machine-learning.

Additional Info

Besides mathematics, I enjoy history, world building, video and board games, heavy music, bonus points when these things are combined. And nothing like a good cup of coffee.